Guide to the William R. and Louise Fielder Sheet Music Collection
Department of Special Collections
- Series 32. Sports
  - That naughty little, sporty little gay golf ball Boston, New York, Chicago: White-Smith Music Publishing Co.,1898 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    Composed by
    Barnet & Corliss' 'Three Little Lambs'
  - Take me out to the ball-game New York: York Music Co.,1908 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    Music by Albert Von Tilzer
    Words by Jack Norworth
    Cover photo of Sam Williams
  - Take me out to the ball-game New York: York Music Co.,1908 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    Cover photo of Lulu Beeson. Possibly first edition.
- Series 33. Transportation
  - The great Rock Island route: song and chorus s.l.: s.n.,1882 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    Words and Music by J. A. Roff
  - Tramway: galop brillant à 4 mains Montreal: A. J. Boucher,n.d. (Box 41, Folder 4)
    Music by L. Gobbaerts
  - Locomotive quick step Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,[1844 -1857] (Box 41, Folder 4)
    Composed by L. Thayer Chadwick
  - The express galop New York: William Hall & Son,[1848 -1858].Montreal: J. W. Herbert & Co. ,[1848 -1858] (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Blue line waltzes Detroit: J. Henry Whittemore,1867 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    Composed by Roe Stephens
  - Lightening express galop (La grand vitesse) Brooklyn: J. W. Smith, Jr. & Bro.,1876 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    Composed by Edward H. Benedict
  - Union line mazurka Pittsburgh: Knake & McGinn,1875 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    Music by L. K. Billings
  - Musard's express train galop New York: William Dressler,n.d. (Box 41, Folder 5)
    Arranged by William Dressler
- Series 34. Uncle Tom's Cabin and Little Eva
  - The death of St. Clare (Little Eva's father), founded upon a scene in 'Uncle Tom's Cabin' Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1852.New York: Gould & Berry ,1852 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    Poetry by M. A. Collier
    Also published by S. Brainard & Co., Cleveland; H. D. Hewitt, New Orleans; G. W. Brainard & Co., Louisville; and C. C. Clapp & Co., Boston
  - I am going there, or, The death of little Eva Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1852.New York: Gould & Berry ,1852 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    Written by John S. Adams
  - Eva to her Papa: song New York: Horace Waters,1853.Boston: G. P. Reed & Co. ,1853 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    Composed by George C. Howard
    Photographer Daguerrotype by Joseph B. Brady; Sarony & Co., New York
    Performed by Little Cordelia Howard
  - Eliza's flight, a scene from Uncle Tom's Cabin Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,1852.New York: Gould & Berry ,1852 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    Music by E. J. Loder
    Written by Miss M. A. Collier
  - Eva's parting, subject taken from Uncle Tom's Cabin Boston: G. P. Reed,1852 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    Composed by F. James
    Written by Miss Mary A. Collier
  - Little Eva: Uncle Tom's guardian angel Boston: John P. Jewett & Company,1852.Cleveland: Jewett, Proctor & Worthington ,1852 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    Music by Manuel Emilio
    Poetry by John G. Whittier
- Series 35. William Vincent Wallace
  - Alary's celebrated polka aria: arranged with variations for the piano forte New York: William Hall & Son,1852.Louisville: G. W. Brainard & Co. ,1852 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    Arranged by William Vincent Wallace
    Performed by Madame Sontag
    Also published by H. D. Hewitt, New Orleans; Colburn & Field, Cincinnati.
  - Good night and pleasant dreams: tyrolien New York: William Hall & Son,1852 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    Words by Anson G. Chester
  - Sweet spirit, hear my prayer! New York: William Hall & Son,1860.London: Cramer, Beale & Co. ,1860 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    Printer Warren Music Stereotyper, New York
    The vocal gems of William Vincent Wallace's grand romantic opera, 'Lurline'
  - Scenes that are brightest: ballad Philadelphia: A. Fiot,n.d.New York: W. Dubois ,n.d. (Box 41, Folder 7)
    Words by Alfred Bunn, Esq.
    Performed by Miss Romer
    Maritana
  - ÔTis the harp in the air: romance Boston: Oliver Ditson & Co.,n.d.Boston: C. C. Clapp & Co. ,n.d. (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Say my heart can this be love: ballad New York: William Hall & Son,1853.London: Cramer, Beale & Co. ,1853 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    Written by Henry C. Watson
    Also published by A. Buttner, St. Petersburg; Brandus & Co., Paris; and Diabelli & Co., Vienna.
  - Sweet spirit, hear my prayer! New York: William Hall & Son,1860 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    William Vincent Wallace's grand romantic opera, 'Lurline'
  - ÔTis the last rose of summer, with variations for the piano forte New York: William Hall & Son,1848 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - La pluie d'or: valse gracieuse pour le piano New York: William Hall & Son,1848.London: Cramer, Beale & Co. ,1848 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    Lithographer: Pearson
  - Impromptu de concert sur la melodie 'Robin Adair' New York: William Hall & Son,1858.Philadelphia: Lee & Walker ,1858 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    Lithographer: Wakelam & Bro.
    Also published by P. P. Werlein & Co., New Orleans and H. McCaffrey, Baltimore.
  - The celebrated witches' dance New York: William Hall & Son,1852 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Sweet spirit, hear my prayer! San Francisco: Sherman & Hyde,1868 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    The grand romantic opera, 'Lurline'
  - The hundredth psalm (Old hundred) New York: William Hall & Son,1854.London: R. Cocks & Co. ,1854 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - La rapidite New York: William Hall & Son,1854.London: Cramer, Beale & Co. ,1854 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    Music by William Vincent Wallace
    Trois Etudes de salon
  - Souvenir de Bellini: fantasie de salon sur l'opera 'Norma' New York: William Hall & Son,1853 -1854 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    Souvenir de l'opera
  - La Mexicana valse New York: William Hall & Son,[1848 -1858] (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Le réve: romance New York: William Hall & Son,1843 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Tremolo schottisch New York: William Hall & Son,1855.London: R. Cocks & Co. ,1855 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Sleeping I dreamed of love New York: William Hall & Son,1855 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    Words by Mrs. Mary E. Hewitt
    La Réve
    Symphonies and accompaniments by John H. Hewitt
  - Grand polka de concert New York: William Hall & Son,1850.London: Cramer, Beale & Co. ,1850 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    Lithographer: F. D'Avignon, New York
  - Village maiden's song: romance for the piano forte New York: William Hall & Son,1851.London: Cramer, Beale & Co. ,1851 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    From :Woodland sketches composed for the piano forte and dedicated to Madame la Princesse Marcelline-Czartorska, née Radziwill
  - I mourn thee but I love no more, companion to Why do I weep for thee: ballad New York: William Hall & Son,1851.London: Cramer, Beale & Co. ,1851 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    Words by Desmond Ryan
  - Sleeping I dreamed of love New York: William Hall & Son,1844 (Box 42, Folder 3)
- Series 36. Women
  - The old maid's prayer: a parody for the piano New York: William A. Pond & Co.,1868 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    Music by Akswezradab
  - I'll be no submissive wife: a ballad New York: William Hall & Son,1838 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    Composed by Alex Lee
  - Mamma, mamma, or, Why don't the men propose: a ballad Boston: James L. Hewitt & Co.,n.d. (Box 42, Folder 4)
    Composed by J. Blewitt
    Poetry by T. Haynes Bayly, Esq.
  - Silver lake quickstep Boston: Henry Tolman,1850 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    Composed by Miss Frances C. Thomas
    Lithographer: Annie R. Smith, del.; Tappan & Bradford's Lith.
- Series 37. Pre-1840 Imprints
  - T'were vain to tell thee all I feel: A Swiss air New York: Dubois & Stodart,[1832] (Box 42, Folder 5)
    Arranged by C. Thibault
    Performed by Miss Hughes
  - The soldier's grave: monody on the death of Sir John Moore Boston: C. Bradlee,[1827 -1834] (Box 42, Folder 5)
    Composed by Thomas Williams
    Written by Rev. Charles Wolfe
  - The celebrated Swiss Guard's march New York: E. Riley,[1820] (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Hither love, hither: a favorite song Baltimore: J. Cole & Son,[1834 -1836] (Box 42, Folder 5)
    Arranged by Sola
  - I'd be a butterfly: a ballad New York: Dubois & Stodart,[1827] (Box 42, Folder 5)
    Composed by T. H. Bayley
    Performed by Mrs. Sharpe
  - The circassian rondo Boston: C. Bradlee,[1837?] (Box 42, Folder 6)
    Composed by M. Holst
  - Araby's daughter Boston: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1826 -1829] (Box 42, Folder 6)
    Composed by G. Kiallmark
    Poetry by Thomas Moore, Esq.
    Performed by Mr. Williamson
  - Let us haste to kelvin grove: a Scotch air New York: Dubois & Stodart,[1827] (Box 42, Folder 6)
    Arranged by J. C. Nightingale
    Performed by Mr. Braham
  - O jours herueux: an aria Philadelphia: Kretschmar & Nunns,[1834 -1836] (Box 42, Folder 6)
    From :La Fiancee
    Instrument :Spanish Guitar
  - La complainte Philadelphia: Kretschmar & Nunns,[1834 -1836] (Box 42, Folder 6)
    Arranged by C. F. Hausman
    Instrument: Spanish Guitar
  - Hinda's appeal to her lover Boston: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1826 -1829] (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Moravian waltz Boston: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1826 -1829] (Box 42, Folder 7)
    Composed by I. L. Dussek
  - I see them on their winding way New York: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1825 -1829] (Box 42, Folder 7)
    Composed by B. Hime
    Words by Bishop Heber
  - Absence, the words, adapted to the favorite air of Rousseau's dream Boston: J. L. Hewitt & Co.,n.d. (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - The drover boy of Appenzell Philadelphia: G. Willig,[1819 -1853] (Box 42, Folder 7)
    Arranged by J. L'Huilier
  - Hours there were New York: Dubois & Stodart,[1827] (Box 42, Folder 8)
    Arranged by Joseph Wade
    Words by Joseph Wade
  - When first we met Boston: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1827 -1829] (Box 42, Folder 8)
    Written by R. Sweeny, Esq.
  - The bridal ring ballad New York: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1836 -1839] (Box 42, Folder 8)
    Composed by G. H. Rodwell
    Performed by F. W. Brandau
    Instrument :Guitar
  - March and rondo New York: Dubois & Stodart,[1827] (Box 42, Folder 8)
    Arranged by M. Holst
    From :Der Freyschutz
  - Hey the bonnie breast knots: a favorite Scotch song Boston: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1826 -1829] (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - The Maltese boatman's song Boston: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1826 -1829] (Box 42, Folder 9)
    Arranged by L. Devereaux
    Performed by The Apollo Society
  - The young cavalier New York: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1832 -1843] (Box 42, Folder 9)
    Arranged by Otto Torp
  - Poor Mary!: a ballad Piot. Meignen & Co.,[1835] (Box 42, Folder 9)
    Arranged by Leopold Meignen
  - St. Patrick's day New York: E. Riley,[1819 -1831] (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Oh leave me to my sorrow Philadelphia: Geo. Willig,[1819 -1842] (Box 42, Folder 9)
    Composed and Arranged by Thomas Moore
    Written by Thomas Moore
  - Dry up your tears. Je pars demain! Il faut quitter Marie Philadelphia: Fiot, Meighen & Co.,[1837 -1839] (Box 42, Folder 10)
    Arranged by A. Schmitz
  - Evening song to the virgin at sea: a duet Boston: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1825 -1829] (Box 42, Folder 10)
    Composed by Mrs. Hemans' Sister
  - A favorite waltz for the piano forte New York: N. Thurston,[1822] (Box 42, Folder 10)
    Composed by Mozart
  - March of the tarters, at a distance, in timour the tartar Boston: G. Graupner,[1811] (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Kintock of Kintock: A favorite Scotch air New York: Dubois & Stodart,1825 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    Instrument: Piano Forte or Harp
  - Hours there were Philadelphia: G. Willig,[1825] (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - I have lov'd thee, dearly lov'd thee Boston: G. Graupner,[1812] (Box 43, Folder 1)
    Composed by Mr. Hook
    Written by Mrs. Robinson
  - Ah can I e'er forget thee love New York: W. Dubois ,[1818] (Box 43, Folder 1)
    Performed by Mr. Nichols
    From :Lord of the Manor
  - La' Clemintina: a favourite waltz Boston: G. Graupner,[1820 -1825] (Box 43, Folder 1)
    Instrument: Piano Forte and Flute
  - The cottage rondo Boston: G. Graupner,[1817] (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Isabel: a celebrated Spanish serenade Philadelphia: G. Willig,[1824 -1827] (Box 43, Folder 2)
    Poetry by Thomas Bayly, Esq.
    Performed by Miss Stephens
  - The downfall of Paris Boston: G. Graupner,[1812] (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Oh ne'er can I the joys forget: a ballad Boston: L. Ostinelli for Jas. Hewitt ,[1825] (Box 43, Folder 2)
    Composed by J. Smith
  - O cold was the climate Philadelphia: ,[1823 -1824] (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - The bird waltz New York: E. Riley,[1823] (Box 43, Folder 2)
    Composed by Francis Panormo
    Instrument: Harp or Piano Forte
  - The Queen of Prussia's favourite waltz; Adieu: a favourite canzonet [verso] [1814] (Box 43, Folder 3)
    Composed by Himmel; Mozart [verso]
  - A selection of favorite waltzes Philadelphia: George Bacon,[1823 -1824] (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Flow on thou shining river: a Portuguese air Baltimore: John Cole,[1825] (Box 43, Folder 3)
    Arranged by Sir John Stevenson
    Moore's National Melodies
  - The morning star: a dance New York: E. Riley,[1818 -1820] (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Captn. Mulligan: a favorite Irish dance New York: E. Riley,[1823] (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Duncan Gray: a Scotch air New York: Dubois & Stodart,[1827] (Box 43, Folder 4)
    Arranged by T. Valentine
  - Soft as yon silver ray that sleeps: a song Boston: G. Graupner,[1820 -1825] (Box 43, Folder 4)
    Composed by J. Bray
    Written by Mrs. Rowson
  - Blink over the burn my sweet laddie: a new Scotch ballad Boston: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1826 -1829] (Box 43, Folder 4)
    Composed by John Smith
  - Cease sweet girl: a canzonet Boston: G. Graupner,[1813] (Box 43, Folder 4)
    Composed by D. D. Roche
  - Marian's my lily, and Flora's my rose: a favorite ballad Boston: G. Graupner,[1816] (Box 43, Folder 4)
    Performed by Mr. J. Jones
  - An Egyptian air, arranged as a rondo Philadelphia: John G. Klemm,[1823 -1831] (Box 43, Folder 5)
    Arranged by T. H. Butler
  - Alice Gray: an admired ballad New York: E. Riley,[1819 -1831] (Box 43, Folder 5)
    Composed by Mrs. P. Millard
  - Mariquita! while those glances. (Mariquita! De tus ojos): a favorite Spanish song Philadelphia: Fiot, Meighen & Co.,[1837 -1839] (Box 43, Folder 5)
    Composed by Madme. de Laborde Bussoni
  - False one I love thee still (Ah perche non posse ordiarte) Baltimore: John Cole & Son,[1834 -1836] (Box 43, Folder 5)
    Composed by V. Bellini
    Performed by Mr. Wood
    La Sonnambula
  - Still so gently o'er me stealing Philadelphia: Osbourn's Music Saloon,[1835 -1842] (Box 43, Folder 5)
    Arranged by P. F. Fallon
  - A soldier's gratitude: a favorite song Boston: G. Graupner & Co.,[1817] (Box 43, Folder 6)
    Performed by Mr. Keene
  - Mélange harmonieux fantaisie New York: Firth & Hall,[1823-1831] (Box 43, Folder 6)
    Composed by W[illia]m Richmond
  - Pas re double Boston: G. Graupner,[1824 -1833] (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - The new Presidents march; Washington's march New York: J. Paff's,[1812] (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Cadets march New York: W. Dubois ,[1817 -1818] (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Duke of York's march Philadelphia: John J. Klemm,[1823 -1831] (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Duke of York's march Boston: G. Graupner,[1817 -1820] (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - The celebrated Swiss Guards march Boston: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1826 -1829] (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - The Knight of the golden crest: a song New York: Dubois & Stodart,[1827] (Box 43, Folder 7)
    Composed by John Barnet
    Written by Harry Stoe Van Dyk
    Performed by Mr. Pearman
  - The nightingale: arranged as a rondino New York: Dubois & Stodart,[1827] (Box 43, Folder 7)
    Arranged by G. E. Fiorini
  - Am I not fondly thine own: a favorite German air Philadelphia: John F. Nunns,[1836 -1839] (Box 43, Folder 8)
    Arranged by John Tanner
  - The vesper bell: a ballad New York: Dubois & Stodart,[1827] (Box 43, Folder 8)
    Composed by J. A. Wade
  - The light guitar: a celebrated serenade Boston: C. Bradlee,[1829 -1834] (Box 43, Folder 8)
    Composed by John Barnett
  - Henry's cottage maid: a favorite song [Boston]: ,[1802 -1803] (Box 43, Folder 8)
    Composed by Pleyel
  - The waterman: a dance New York: E. Riley,[1818 -1820] (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - The Spanish dance or Gen. Riego's march Boston: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1824] (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Oh! say not woman's heart is bought Boston: S. Wood,[1822] (Box 43, Folder 9)
    Composed by John Whitaker
    Performed by Mrs. French
  - Now at moonlight's fairy hour: a favorite duett New York: J. A. & W. Geib,[1818 -1821] (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - In happier hours: a German air Boston: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1826 -1829] (Box 43, Folder 9)
    Composed by W[illia]m Staunton, Jr.
    Poetry by Thomas H. Bayly, Esq.
    Performed by Miss Mallet
  - ÔTis love in the heart: the admired rondo Boston: G. Graupner,[1820 -1825] (Box 43, Folder 9)
    Composed by Cha[rle]s E. Horn
    Poetry by S. J. Arnold, Esq.
    Bride of Abydos
  - Fare thee well! Philadelphia: G. Willig,[1817 -1818] (Box 43, Folder 10)
    Poetry by Lord Byron
    Ah Perdona
  - Farewell to my harp: a ballad Boston: John Ashton,[1824 -1833] (Box 43, Folder 10)
    Composed by Charles E. Horn
  - The Albion waltz New York: Atwill's Music Saloon,1835 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    Composed by Rich[ar]d B. Taylor
  - Thou'rt false to me: a ballad Boston: John Ashton,[1824 -1833] (Box 43, Folder 10)
    Composed by Geo[rge] E. Farmer
  - Love good night: a ballad Boston: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1826 -1829] (Box 43, Folder 10)
    Arranged by Will[ia]m Hawes
    Der Freischutz
  - Evening song of the Tyrolese peasants Philadelphia: Geo[rge] Willig,[1828] (Box 44, Folder 1)
    Composed and Arranged by I. T. Norton
  - She sung but afraid of her own sweet voice New York: E. Riley,[1819 -1831] (Box 44, Folder 1)
    Composed by F. W. Crouch
    Poetry by D. Weir, Esq.
  - Country dances New York: E. Riley,[1823] (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - The bath waltz: a popular air arranged as a rondo Boston: G. Graupner,[1820] (Box 44, Folder 1)
    Arranged by Thomas Tomlins
  - The cottage rondo Boston: G. Graupner,[1817] (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Oh! yes we often mention her, in answer to the celebrated ballad 'Oh! no, We never mention her' New York: E. S. Messier,[1827 -1833] (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - The chieftain: A favorite ballad Philadelphia: G. E. Blake,[1823 -1824] (Box 44, Folder 2)
    Written by T. Campbell
  - Sing not my song yet: a ballad New York: E. S. Mesier,[1828 -1834] (Box 44, Folder 2)
    Composed by J. A. Wade, Esq.
    Poetry by J. A. Wade, Esq.
  - A celebrated polacca, arranged as a rondino New York: Dubois & Stodart,[1827] (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - The Caledonian hunt, with variations New York: J. A. & W. Geib,[1818 -1823] (Box 44, Folder 2)
    Composed by T. Latour
  - Le portrait: romance New York: Jos[ia]h Willson, Jr.,[1720?] (Box 44, Folder 3)
    Instrument: Piano or Harp
  - Flow on thou shining river: a Portuguese air New York: ,[1818] (Box 44, Folder 3)
    Composed by Sir John Stevenson
  - Oh! yes we often mention her: a ballad In answer to 'Oh! no, we never mention her' New York: Dubois & Stodart,[1828 -1834] (Box 44, Folder 3)
    Composed by J. Barnett
  - My [...] lute New York: Dubois & Stodart,[1823 -1826] (Box 44, Folder 3)
    Composed by Thomas Moore, Esq
  - Marche favorite du regiment austrichien Philadelphia: G. Willig,[1819 -1853] (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Robin Adair: the much admired ballad Philadelphia: G. Willig's Musical Magazine,[1818] (Box 44, Folder 4)
    Arranged by W. Reeve
    Performed by Mr. Philipps
  - When shall we three meet again: a ballad Boston: G. Graupner,n.d. (Box 44, Folder 4)
    Composed by W[illia]m Horsley
  - Erin is my home Boston: Oliver Ditson,[1844 -1857] (Box 44, Folder 4)
    Arranged by Moschelles
    Performed by Mr. Dempster
  - Wake from your slumbers New York: Firth & Hall,1831 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    Composed by Wilhelm Jucho
    Poetry by Th[omas] E. Blanche, Esq.
    Performed by Mr. E. Fehrman
  - La Parisienne: a translation of the celebrated ode New York: E. S. Meiser,[1816 -1832] (Box 44, Folder 4)
    Composed by Casimir Delavigne
    Performed by Mrs. Austin and the Chorus of the Park Theatre
  - Oh! give me the hills, the woods, and the mountains New York: Firth & HAll,1836 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    Poetry by W. C. Bacon, Esq.
    Performed by Mr. W. R. Dempster
  - Grand march of Cinderella New York: Bourne Depository of Arts,1831 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    Composed by Signor G. Pons
  - The favorite Vienna waltz New York: W. Dubois ,[1818] (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - The hunting chorus New York: E. Riley,1828 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    Arranged by A. Professor
    Instrument :Flute and Piano Forte
  - Sounds so joyful Philadelphia: Fiot, Meighen & Co.,[1837 -1839] (Box 44, Folder 5)
    Arranged by L[eopold] Meignen
    Bellini's 'La Sonnambula' Guitar
  - Ah! don't mingle one human feeling (Ah! non giunge uman pensiero) Philadelphia: Fiot, Meighen & Co.,[1837 -1839] (Box 44, Folder 6)
    Bellini's 'La Sonnambula'
  - The Switzer's song of home: a ballad with English and German words Baltimore: Geo. Willig, Jr.,n.d. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Lord Moira's welcome New York: E. Riley,[1819 -1831] (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Come away to the glen Boston: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1826 -1829] (Box 44, Folder 6)
    Englishmen in India
  - Love has been there Baltimore: John Cole,[1824 -1834] (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Von Weber's last waltz Philadelphia: G. Willig,1832 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - On the death of Miss Caroline Gourlay. Weep! weep! for the maid of the song is dead Philadelphia: G. Willig,1835 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    Composed and Arranged by J. L'Huiler
  - Ah! don't mingle Philadelphia: Geo. Willig,[1819 -1853] (Box 44, Folder 7)
    Arranged by P. M. Wolfsiefer
  - My ain kind dearie New York: Dubois & Stodart,1927 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Bonaparte's grand coronation march Baltimore: John Cole,[1814 -834] (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Gertrude's dream waltz (Box 44, Folder 7)
    Composed by Ludwig von Beethoven
    Handwritten manuscript, bound with 'Ah! Don't Mingle, finale to Bellini's celebrated opera of La Sonnambula, arranged for the guitar, arranged by P. M. Wolfsiefer, Philadelphia: Geo. Willig, [1819 -1853].' Box 44, Folder 7.
  - Benedetta (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Le baiser d'amour (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Little Sue: a favorite ballad sung at the Vauxhall Philadelphia: G. Willig,[1816 -1817] (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - My heart with love is beating: a favorite song Philadelphia: Geo. Willig,1828 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    Arranged by T. E. Cubert
  - As I view these scenes so charming (Di ravviso o luoghi amenir): an air Philadelphia: Fiot, Meighen & Co.,[1837 -1839] (Box 44, Folder 8)
    Composed by Bellini
  - Lovely Rose: a song adapted to the popular Venetian air Philadelphia: G. E. Blake ,[1820].New York: R. Meetz ,[1820] (Box 44, Folder 8)
    From :Opescator dell'onda
    Instrument :Piano Forte or Harp
  - Benedetta sia la madre: canzoncina New York: James L. Hewitt & Co.,[1830 -1832] (Box 44, Folder 8)
    Arranged by C. M. Sola
    Performed by Mrs. Solomon
  - Whilst I listen to thy voice: a favorite ballad New York: W. Dubois ,[1821] (Box 44, Folder 9)
    Composed by Sir J[ohn] A. Stevenson
    Performed by Mr. Julius Metz
  - Waltz from the opera of La Somnambula Boston: Charles H. Keith,1836 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    From :La Somnambula
  - But who shall see! New York: W. Dubois,[1820] (Box 44, Folder 9)
    Performed by Mr. Brennan
    T. Moore's Sacred Melodies
  - My ain fire side: a celebrated song Philadelphia: G. Willig,[1819 -1850] (Box 44, Folder 9)
    Arranged by John Parry
    Performed by Mr. Sinclair
  - Lassie wi'the lint white lock: a favorite Scotch ballad Philadelphia: Geo. Willig,[1823] (Box 44, Folder 9)
    Composed and Arranged by T. W. H. B. B.
  - The Lass O'Gowrie: a favorite Scotch melody New York: Firth & Hall,[1832] (Box 44, Folder 10)
    Performed by Mr. W. G. Plumer
  - Home! Sweet home! Baltimore: John Cole,[1824 -1826] (Box 44, Folder 10)
    Performed by Miss M. Tree
    From :Clari, or The Maid of Milan